# **Valentin EKEU TIEMENI**

## Green Card holder - No Sponsorship required

Hard worker; Natural problem solver; Analytical thinker with strong interpersonal skills; Calm under pressure.

Landover, Maryland 20785

+1 (240) 441-7066

ektiva2013@gmail.com

Website: https://ektiva.github.io/

#### Summary

I am a Software Engineer with experience building multi-tiered applications, created full-stack .NET Application with C#, Angular, MVC, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. In addition, I have an in-depth understanding of Object-Oriented Programming, Agile development methodology, analysis, designs and SOLID principle. I'm a really motivated person and able to learn new technologies or concepts very fast. I'm capable of handling multiple tasks and I have strong customer service skills.

## **Professional Experience**

Software Engineer | Regency Management Services, LLC – Brandywine, MD

February 2020 - Present

Working in Agile environment with a team to build an online system to manage multiples furniture stores distributed in several sales division and sales district. Responsibilities:

- Analyze user requirements from the Scrum Master and convert it to design documents.
- Designed and implemented Auth Gateway for authentication by scaffolding ASP.Net identity.
- Elaborate the Coding Standards and Best Programming Practices for the team.
- Designed and implemented the different model (user, domain, department...) including the hierarchyld type and fluent validation.
- Create the initial database instance using EF code first and write consistent LINQ query to access SQL Server database.
- Implement RESTful ASP.NET Web APIs using HttpClient and Ajax to communicate with database.
- Tested the API with Postman and ensure that data is presented in JSON format
- Managed database structure using Fluid API and data formatting with Data Annotations including Regex.
- Completed unit and integration testing with MSTest and xUnit unit tests in C#, with Swagger for API and with Jasmine-based tests run with Karma in Angular.
- Configure and use azure pipeline for CI/CD, Setup and managed azure app insight to monitor the lives applications.
- Build a reactive and responsive UI for the client side login, registration and merchandize with Angular 8.
- Setup and implemented azure service bus (topic and queue) for asynchronous transfer of data and state between our different services.
- Design and implemented the repository pattern.
- Override the OnModelCreating method and use the ModelBuilder API to configure our model.

#### Software Engineer | Revature – Reston, MD

October 2019 – January 2020

- Working with a team to build multi-tiered applications, created full-stack .NET Application with C#, Angular, MVC, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS... Responsibilities:

- Involved and participated in the overall application lifecycle of 2 mains projects
- Designed and implemented the MVC design pattern of <u>pizza parlor</u> project
- Setup and implemented Redis database to store customer basket of pizza parlor project
- Writing, implementing and testing code, refining and rewriting it as necessary.
- Tested functionality with unit tests written using Visual Studio NUnit Test .Net core.
- Resolve complex technical design issues (Date problem, EF migration, many to many relationship, communications between model-view-controller...)
- Designed and Build reactive Angular front-ends using custom services to asynchronously deliver RxJS Observables with data from HttpClient calls to API.(<u>a-bank</u> project)
- Develop and consume (from Angular) REST (WebAPI) and SOAP (WCF) based services.
- Tested the API with Postman, visit Can I Use to optimize HTTML code and user browser experience.
- Managed source code and collaborate with team using Git and slack.
- Set Up local container registry for test deployments/builds.

## Production Supervisor | Walmart – Washington Blvd, Arbutus, MD

October 2017 – June 2019

- Manage production team and Develop best practices, routines and innovative solutions to improve production rates and quality of output.

#### Metrology/Industrial Engineer | PISE - Cameroon

March 2014 - Sept. 2017

Responsible of metrology and innovation department and supervision of a high performing team that is capable of analysing, troubleshooting, and repairing broken equipment, as well as performing preventive maintenance tasks.

## Industrial Engineer | AMLA – Yaounde, Cameroon

Jan 2013 - February 2014

 Analysis, Design and Implementation of a Gauging and Tank-Strapping Software (using Java & SQL) based on a volumetric approach and the information System of the Station, using scientific analysis and mathematical models.

#### Responsibilities:

- Designed the entire application using UML and OOP design pattern.
- Get user requirement from the company COO and translate into technical requirements.
- Modeling the application (use case diagram, class diagram, sequence diagram, deployment diagram, prototype, calculation model...)
- Define and implement the business logic (volumetric vs geometry tank-strapping)
- Build responsive, functional and great looking UI of the application using Java Swing, NetBeans and 3rd party library look and feel.
- Design the database using SQL design pattern
- Use PowerAMC to design class diagram and generate custom code source for java and PHP and Script for SQL.

## Engineering Internship | SELUNG Engineering – Douala, Cameroon

July - September 2012

Design and Implementation of a database (using SQL+ACCESS) for the management of materials, tools, and manufactured products at SELUNG; Design
and implementation of service & maintenance plans for SELUNG's machine tools.

October 2007 - July 2010

- Data base management, word processing, complete forms in accordance with company procedures

## **Education**

## Bootcamp / Software Engineering | Revature - Reston, Virginia

July 2019 - September 2019

- Project base Bootcamp where we created full stack web application using .Net and Angular curriculum, including C#, SQL, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Angular 6, Azure DevOps, Docker, Algorithm and Data Structure....

## Master Degree / Design Engineering | National Advanced School of Engineering, Yaounde

Sept. 2010 - July 2013

- Engineering and Production Management; Design and Development of New Products and Production Systems; Quality; Information System (Databases, Networking, Programming); Operational Research, Human Resources Management and Ergonomics, Health, Safety and Environment

## Bachelor's Degree in Mathematics (2008) | University of Yaounde 1

Sept. 2004 – July 2008

Numerical Analysis, Game Theory, Descriptive Statistics and Probability; Operational Research, Scientific Computing and Data Analysis, Decisional Statistic, Optimisation.

## **Skills and Abilities**

#### **Technical Skills**

- Web Technologies: ASP.NET Web API, .NET MVC, Web Services, HTML5, AJAX & JQuery, CSS, Angular.
- Programming Language: JavaScript, Java, C#, Python, VB/VBA, C+, Matlab, PHP.
- Database & Storage: SQLite, SQL, SQL Server, MySQL, NoSQL, Redis, ACCESS, AWS, Microsoft Azure SQL Database.
- Devops: Kubernetes, Postman, Docker, Git, SonarCloud, Azure DevOps (CI/CD, Application Insights, Service Bus, Resource group, SQL server/database, App Service...).
- Amazon Web Services: IAM, AWS EC2, AWS EBS, AWS AMI.
- Strong proficiency with Microsoft Office applications and statistical tools (Excel, Word, Minitab, PowerPoint...)
- Lean Six Sigma green belt level capability with strong Knowledge in application of DMAIC, DFSS and Lean Tools.
- Solid understanding of Object Oriented Programming, SOLID principle, business and IT processes.

## **Communication & interpersonal Skills**

- Excellent team-working and Leadership abilities. Good integration in the workplace.
- Eager, ambitious, and adaptable to change
- Excellent attention to detail and strong organizational and time management abilities
- Heightened sense of Work Ethics and Discipline Standards, practical abilities, rigor and effectiveness skills

#### Language

- French: Native
- English: Proficient